# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

#### FRIDAH NDINDA KIOKO

P.O BOX 41836 – 00100, NAIROBI KENYA

PHONE: +254725932072 ,+254722-789 634 ,0722330381

Email: kiokofri@gmail.com

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

NATIONALITY : Kenyan

ID NUMBER : 24535681

DATE OF BIRTH : 16<sup>th</sup> September 1985

LANGUAGES : English, Swahili

RELIGION : Christian

To apply and exploit my Financial Knowledge, skills & expertise to a distinguished institution which can offer a great variety of tasks and provide challenging opportunities in the field of International Finance, Capital Budgeting, Credit management, and/or dealing of Financial Instruments in a manner compatible with the current business environment and adding value to all stakeholders in the world of business as well as to enable the organization achieve its set goals & objectives.

#### EXECUTIVE SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS AND EXPERIENCE

Currently, I am working at KCA University as Credit Controller. In addition I have more than five years experience in field of Financial Management, Grant and Donor fund Management, Budgeting & Budget Analysis, Credit management & Capital budgeting gained from the past. I am a holder of Master of Science degree (Msc) in Finance and Investments obtained from The University of Nairobi. I hold a Bachelor of Commerce (Upper Second Class Honors) degree with specialization in Accounting Option, from Kenyatta University. I am a qualified Accountant with CPA (K) Certification and a registered member of ICPAK.

#### PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Proven ability to analyze complex business issues and identify, design and implement effective practical recommendations
- Highly motivated in my work and able to spread this motivation to others in a professional and exciting way.
- Fast learner, embracing diversity, ability to combine tasks and excel in all such tasks.
- Ability to work in progressive multi-cultural organization that will enable me to contribute to its welfare and exercise my talents& skills to the fullest.
- Have strong analytical and creative problem solving skills.

## EDUCATION BACKGROUND

<b>Period</b>	Institution	<b>Examination and Grades</b>
2012-2014	University of Nairobi	Master of Science (Finance & Investments)
2005-2009	Kenyatta University	Bachelor of Commerce(Accounting Option)
2000-2003	Muthetheni Girls High Sch.	Second Class (Upper Division)  K.C.S.E Grade A- (Minus)
2000-2003	Mudiemeni Giris Figii Scii.	K.C.S.E Glade A- (willus)
1991-1999	Kiundwani Primary School	K.C.P.E 503 out of <b>700</b> Marks

# PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

Diploma in Credit Management from Kenya School of Credit Management.

2009 Certified Public Accountant of Kenya (CPA-K)

#### **OTHER SKILLS**

-Customer Relationship Skills- Marketing Society of Kenya (MSK)

## -Computer Skills

- Office suites: MS Word, MS Excel, MS Access, MS Power Point
- Knowledge in ERP
- Qualified in Quick books and Sage

- Report writing skills, Communication and Inter personal skills

## WORK EXPERIENCE

Period Institution Position held

March 2013-To Date KCA-University - Credit Controller

#### **Duties & Responsibilities.**

- Developing & executing of Credit management policy for the University in relation to the University's Financial Policy
- Overseeing and building the access control system of the University's premises.
- Developing end-to-end Cash flow projections and monitoring for the University.
- Custodian of all debt collection documents for future reference like referral to debt collectors
- Giving collection projections monthly and per trimester.
- Providing all the debtors audit schedules i.e bad debt write offs, provisions for bad debts and debtors aging.
- Overseeing credit control functions of the university.
- Analyses of debtors accounts and identify doubtful debts for reference to debt collectors.
- Working with debt collectors (Metropol) in providing all required documentation and support

Period Institution Position held

2010- 2013 Church Army Africa - Senior Finance Officer -

## **Duties & Responsibilities.**

1. Overseeing all financial activities of the institution including Budgeting, Resource Allocation, payment approvals, contracts appraisal and Revenue forecasting among others.

- 2. Allocation of college resources to various departments and monitoring to ensure that its usage is in compliance with the set Financial policy of the institution.
- 3. Ensuring quality of accounts and other services to students and other departments;
- **4.** Developing and maintaining the long-term strategic financial plan of the college; Guiding the Principal and staff through medium and long-term program planning, including goal setting;
- **5.** Being an active member of the Senior Management Team of the college, fostering and supporting the student focused goals and aims of the college.
- **6.** Management of grants and donation of the college and students
- 7. Leading the Senior Management Team through the annual budgetary sessions, preparing the annual operating and capital budget and implementing budgetary controls.
- **8.** Encouraging and overseeing external grants, with the assistance of the principal, ensuring compliance with the donor reporting requirements;
- **9.** Preparation of management reports including provision of Financial advice and support to the Board to enable them make sound business decisions.
- 10. Overseeing processing of payroll.
- **11.** Providing leadership in putting in place appropriate internal controls and implementation of financial policies
- 12. Preparation and leading External audit

Period	Institution	Position held
April 2009-August 2010	Dorcas Aid International	Project Accountant
	Hiv-Aids Programme -Machakos	

#### **Key Responsibilities**

- 1. Making daily entries on all expenditures in the books of account
- 2. Advice on all the financial accounting and management issues
- 3. Management of accounting records, financial statements and other financial reports to assess accuracy and conformance to reporting and procedural standards
- 4. Making financial reports for the local partner and development partners

- 5. Ensuring that the systems and workflow between Finance and the Grants section remains strong and efficient with much on good quality and timely donor reports.
- 6. Compiling monthly projects income and expenditures reports
- 7. Receiving all money/Funds of the projects and making sure it is banked before any spending
- 8. Collating and analyzing the operational budgets for the country programs, paying particular attention to funding gaps.
- 9. Preparation of budgets and assist in proposal writing.
- 10. Oversee the development, Implementation and review of financial management systems for the projects
- 11. Assist in procurement of fixed assets
- 12. Giving financial technical advice to the projects and the local partner in general
- 13. Overseeing all IGAs done by the beneficiaries and training the beneficiaries on simple methods of book keeping.
- 14. Encouraging and overseeing external grants, with the assistance of the project manager, ensuring compliance with the donor reporting requirements
- 15. Capacity building of groups doing income generating activities in conjunction with KARI KATUMANI.
- 16. Allocation and distribution of seeds given by KARI KATUMANI to beneficiaries and carrying monitoring and evaluation of the seeds project
- 17. Preparation of agreements for clients for awarding of capital in kind for IGA.

Skills gained: Team work, result based management, formulating and maintaining partnerships with government structures and other stakeholders, Cash flow projections and management, knowledge management, mainstreaming of cross cutting issues in programming, working capital management, financial analysis, donor compliance requirements and reporting, drafting of a financial procedures manual, comprehensive budgeting for cost centers, management of scarce resources, monitoring and evaluation skills, capacity building skill, credit management and human resources skills.

Period Institution Position held

# **Duties & Responsibilities**

- 1. -Collecting deposits from customers
- 2. -Computing loans for customers
- 3. -Assessing worthiness of loan applicants
- 4. -Preparing contracts for successful loan applicants

## SOCIAL ACTIVITIES/RESPONSIBILITIES

<b>Date</b>	Institution	Responsibility & achievements	
2005-2009	Kenyatta University	Organizing Secretary – Kenyatta University	
	Account	ing Students Association (ASA)	
		-Acquired Teamwork and Leadership skills.	

#### WORKSHOPS AND SEMINARS ATTENDED

Fraud detection and prevention organized by Institute of Capacity Building KCA University

Budgeting formulation, implementation and control organized by Hammond, Tutu and Gunther

Credit management seminar organized by Kenya School of Credit Management.

Customer care organized by Marketing Society of Kenya.

Hiv/Aids organized by Dorcas aid international

# **OUTSTANDING ACHIEVEMENTS**

**2013**-1. Participated in review of financial policy manual for KCA University.

- 2. Spear headed Integration of all financial software in KCA University and incorporate Internal controls to cab fraud which had re-occurred severally.
  - 2012-Spear headed development and implementation of college management software in Carlile college (Church Army)
  - Member of Marketing Advisory Committee of Carlile college which lead the growth of the college population and image
  - Member of Redeemed Gospel church (JVEC) Development committee which facilitated the relocation and settlement of the church to a bigger land.
- 2011- Developed the first consolidated budget in history of Church Army
- -Championed Upgrade of finance software in Church Army -Facilitated External audit in Church Army which changed the audit report which had been qualified in 2010

## HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Reading business, inspirational and motivational books and journals.
- Traveling adventure, socializing and watching a lot of business news.
- Participating in voluntary work in the community.
- Mentoring and giving out motivational talks to young people.

# **GUIDING PRINCIPLE**

"True success is genuine satisfaction, happiness and contentment with yourself and the world around you."

# REFEREES:

PAPTRICK MUTETI MUIA
PROJECT MANAGER –DORCAS AID
INTERNATIONAL
MACHAKOS HIV/AIDS PROGRAMME
SOSPETER IKONYA NJOROGE

**GRANT OFFICER** 

APHIAplus Western Kenya

P.O BOX 19128-40123

**KISUMU** 

MOBILE PHONE .0724949610

E.MAIL:

Snjoroge@aphiapluswesternkenya.org

Rev. Capt Richard Mayabi

General Secretary

Church Army Africa

P.O Box 72584-00200

Cell phone no.0721305079

Email:info@churcharmyafrica.net